Register of the Albert Glotzer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Shachtmanite Period Papers, 1940-1958
  - Unaffiliated international organization documents and issuances
    - German (Folder 39: 5)
      Circular letter by Internationale Kommunisten Deutschlands, 1944; Mitteilsungsblätter der I.K.D. no. 2 (1946)
    - Indian (Folder 39: 6)
      Janata (Praja Socialist Party) vol. 11 no. 44/45 (1956)
    - South African (Folder 39: 7)
      The Revolutionary Communist (Workers International League). 1945 August, November
  - Miscellany, 1940-1957
    - Shorthand reporting papers, 1941-1957 (Folder 39: 8)
      Correspondence, samples of court transcripts, membership list, and printed matter, relating to shorthand reporting work carried out by Albert Glotzer, and to the Federation of Shorthand Reporters
    - Ciliga, Ante, "A Conversation with Lenin,", circa 1940s (Folder 39: 9)
      Galleys of article published in Politics,
    - Miscellanea re Soviet Union, circa 1943-1957 (Folder 39: 10)
      Printed matter and near-print material, circa 1943-1957. Includes circulated protest of motion picture Mission to Moscow, and United Nations report on forced labor
    - Miscellanea, 1942-1957 (Folder 39: 11)
      Printed matter and near-print material, 1942-1957, re Jews, Spain, World War II resistance, United Automobile Workers Union, and other subjects. Includes Free Men against the Gestapo issued by the Committee for Rebirth of European Democracy
- Social Democratic Period Papers, 1958-1999
  - Biographical file
    - Biographical data, 1978-1999 (Folder 40: 1)
      Biographical sketches, data for biographical directory entries, 70th birthday party celebration letters, and clippings, 1978-1999
    - Foster, Charles G., "Al Glotzer: Peripatetic Pitmanite," Shorthand Reporter, 1974 March (Folder 40: 2)
    - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1977-1978 (Folder 40: 3)
      Correspondence with U.S. Central Intelligence Agency, Army Intelligence Agency, Federal Bureau of Investigation and Department of State, 1977-1978, together with released photocopies of government case file documents re Glotzer
    - Obituaries, 1999 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1960-1997, undated
      - 1960-1979 (Folder 40: 5)
      - 1980-1989 (Folder 40: 6)
      - 1990-1997 (Folder 40: 7)
    - Abel, Lionel, 1984-1986 (Folder 40: 8)
    - Alexander, Robert J., 1973-1986 (Folder 40: 9)
    - Archer, John, 1977-1980 (Folder 40: 10)
    - Atlas, James, 1990-1997 (Folder 40: 11)
    - Bell, Daniel, 1959-1990 (Folder 40: 12)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1964-1997
      - 1964-1989 (Folder 40: 13)
      - 1990-1997 (Folder 40: 14)
    - Bernick, Paul, 1990 (Folder 40: 15)
    - Boydston, Jo Ann (and Center for Dewey Studies), 1977-1996
      Includes printed writings by Boydston
      - 1977-1992 (Folder 41: 1)
      - 1993-1996 (Folder 41: 2)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1977 (Folder 41: 3)
    - Breitman, George, 1974-1986 (Folder 41: 4)
    - Brooks, Thomas, 1982-1990 (Folder 41: 5)
    - Broué, Pierre, 1980-1991 (Folder 41: 6)
    - Buchman, Alexander, 1985-1997
      - 1985-1991 (Folder 41: 7)
      - 1991-1997 (Folder 41: 8)
    - Burbank, David T., 1959-1987 (Folder 41: 9)
    - Bush, George and Barbara (birthday greeting), 1991 (Folder 41: 10)
    - Carmichael, Joel, 1988-1997 (Folder 41: 11)
    - Carroll, Wendel Rodman, 1993-1995 (Folder 41: 12)
    - Challinor, Raymond, 1991 (Folder 41: 13)
    - Chenoweth, Eric, 1979-1993 (Folder 41: 14)
    - Chomsky, Noam (to Hugo Oehler), 1978 (Folder 41: 15)
    - Clark, Joseph, 1980-1981 (Folder 41: 16)
    - Class, Sam, 1970-1990 (Folder 41: 17)
    - Cogen, Charles, 1984-1994 (Folder 41: 18)
    - Cohen, Barney, 1975-1992 (Folder 41: 19)
    - Cohn, Werner, 1983-1989 (Folder 41: 20)
      Includes printed writings by Cohn
    - Conquest, Robert, 1992-1993 (Folder 41: 21)
    - Cornelissen, Igor, 1987 (Folder 42: 1)
    - Cowl, Carl (re Hugo Oehler), 1982 (Folder 42: 2)
    - Crawford, Ted (and Revolutionary History), 1988-1993 (Folder 42: 3)
    - Curtiss, Charles, 1986-1993 (Folder 42: 4)
    - Decter, Midge, 1982-1986 (Folder 42: 5)
    - Despres, Leon M., 1966-1997 (Folder 42: 6)
    - Dewar, Hugo and Margaret, 1978-1981 (Folder 42: 7)
    - Diamond, Joseph M., 1985-1997 (Folder 42: 8)
    - Diehl, Mary (re Jack and Morris Childs), 1979-1981 (Folder 42: 9)
    - Draper, Hal, 1975 (Folder 42: 10)
    - Drucker, Peter, 1988-1992 (Folder 42: 11)
      Includes typescript review by James T. Burnett of Drucker's book Max Shachtman and His Left
    - Easson, Michael (re Harry Wicks), 1993 (Folder 42: 12)
    - Elliott, Stuart, 1978 (Folder 42: 13)
    - Erber, Ernest (to Alan Wald), 1984 (Folder 42: 14)
    - Evans, Les (and Pathfinder Press), 1976-1979 (Folder 42: 15)
    - Farrell, James T., 1974-1979 (Folder 42: 16)
      Includes printed writings by Farrell
    - Feferman, Anita Burdman, 1991-1992 (Folder 42: 17)
    - Feldman, Paul, 1970-1994 (Folder 42: 18)
      Includes typescript by Feldman re 1980 presidential election prospects
    - Feuer, Lewis S., 1985-1995 (Folder 42: 19)
      Includes reader's report to publisher re Feuer's manuscript on John Dewey
    - Fishman, Sam, 1977-1983 (Folder 42: 20)
    - Flynn, Dennis, 1986-1987 (Folder 42: 21)
      Includes issues of the Friends of the James T. Farrell Collection Newsletter edited by Flynn
    - Fraser, C. Gerald (and New York Times Book Review re C. L. R. James), 1985 (Folder 42: 22)
    - Freedman, Rita, 1980-1994 (Folder 42: 23)
    - Friend, Ephraim, 1972-1987 (Folder 42: 24)
    - Gates, John and Lillian, 1992-1997 (Folder 42: 25)
      Includes obituary of Gates
    - Gebert, Konstanty, 1990-1991 (Folder 42: 26)
    - Geltman, Emanuel, 1978-1994, undated (Folder 42: 27)
    - Genecin, Milton (to Alan Wald), 1984 (Folder 42: 28)
    - Gershman, Carl, 1974-1993 (Folder 42: 29)
    - Gertz, Elmer, 1986-1997 (Folder 42: 30)
      Includes printed writings by Gertz
    - Gladstone, Joe, 1991 (Folder 43: 1)
    - Glotzer, Marguerite, 1984 (Folder 43: 2)
    - Glotzer, Robert H., 1981 (Folder 43: 3)
    - Goldwater, Walter, 1981-1984 (Folder 43: 4)
      Includes printed article about Goldwater
    - Green, Gil, 1992 (Folder 43: 5)
    - Grosby, Steven, 1982-1985 (Folder 43: 6)
    - Groves, Daisy, 1988 (Folder 43: 7)
      Includes obituary of Reginald Groves
    - Haberkern, Ernie, 1990-1995 (Folder 43: 8)
    - Hacker, David (re Max Shachtman), 1995 (Folder 43: 9)
    - Haston, Jock and Millie, 1965-1986 (Folder 43: 10)
    - Haynes, John Earl, 1986-1987 (Folder 43: 11)
    - Held, Abraham B., 1973-1996 (Folder 43: 12)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1975-1989
      Includes printed writings by Hook
      - 1975-1984 (Folder 43: 13)
      - 1985-1989 (Folder 43: 14)
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1986-1993 (Folder 43: 15)
      Includes printed issuances
    - Howe, Irving, 1964-1989, undated (Folder 43: 16)
    - Isaacs, Harold R. (to Alan Wald), 1974 (Folder 43: 17)
    - Isserman, Maurice, 1985 (Folder 43: 18)
    - Johanningsmeier, Ed, 1986 (Folder 43: 19)
      Includes photocopy of Johanningsmeier's notes on his interview with Glotzer
    - Johnpoll, Bernard K., 1970 (Folder 43: 20)
    - Jones, Edward (re Juliet Stuart Poyntz), 1993 (Folder 43: 21)
    - Kahn, Tom, 1973-1985 (Folder 43: 22)
      Includes obituaries of Kahn
    - Kaplan, Morris A., 1983-1993 (Folder 43: 23)
    - Kelly, Daniel, 1990 (Folder 43: 24)
    - Kemble, Penn, 1973-1997 (Folder 43: 25)
    - Kempton, Murray, 1960 (Folder 43: 26)
    - Kessler, Ralph, 1988-1997 (Folder 43: 27)
    - King, David (and Francis Wyndham), 1974-1987 (Folder 43: 28)
    - Klehr, Harvey, 1983-1990 (Folder 44: 1)
    - Koch, Edward I., 1971 (Folder 44: 2)
    - Kugler, Israel, 1980-1992 (Folder 44: 3)
    - Kurtz, Paul (and Prometheus Books), 1990-1994 (Folder 44: 4)
    - Labedz, Leopold, 1977-1985 (Folder 44: 5)
    - Lasky, Melvin, 1984-1985 (Folder 44: 6)
    - Leopold, Louis, 1990-1995 (Folder 44: 7)
    - Levine, Jack, 1977-1989 (Folder 44: 8)
    - Lofman, Jacob, 1975-1989 (Folder 44: 9)
    - Lowenstein, Allard, 1966-1969 (Folder 44: 10)
    - McCourt, Frank, 1997 (Folder 44: 11)
    - McDonald, John, 1977-1987 (Folder 44: 12)
    - McMillan, Jack, 1990, undated (Folder 44: 13)
    - Matheson, Min, 1987-1992 (Folder 44: 14)
      Includes death notice
    - Meltz, Eva Stolar, 1976-1979 (Folder 44: 15)
    - Miller, Barry, 1997 (Folder 44: 16)
    - Monaghan, James B. (re Thomas J. O'Flaherty), 1994-1995 (Folder 44: 17)
    - Montalvan, Wilfredo (and Partido Social Demócrata de Nicaragua), 1980 (Folder 44: 18)
    - Morrow, Felix (to Alan Wald), 1984 (Folder 44: 19)
    - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1977-1993 (Folder 44: 20)
      Includes typescript "Socialism/Capitalism Discussion Paper" by Muravchik
    - Myers, Constance Ashton, 1972-1978 (Folder 44: 21)
      Includes photocopy of Myers' notes on her interview with Max Shachtman
    - Nedava, Joseph, 1983-1988 (Folder 44: 22)
      Includes printed writing by Nedava
    - Newby, Richard, undated (Folder 44: 23)
    - Novack, George, 1979 (Folder 44: 24)
    - Osgood, Rae, 1995 (Folder 44: 25)
    - Ostroff, Harold, 1972-1987 (Folder 44: 26)
    - Panken, Irving, 1984-1988 (Folder 44: 27)
    - Passin, Herbert, 1983-1991 (Folder 44: 28)
    - Paturis, Cleo Mitchell, 1980-1994 (Folder 44: 29)
    - Pelinka-Martová, Marta, 1997 (Folder 44: 30)
    - Phelps, Christopher, 1991-1998 (Folder 44: 31)
    - Plastrik, Stanley, 1980-1981 (Folder 44: 32)
    - Poole, Thomas R., 1972-1978 (Folder 44: 33)
    - Porter, Paul R., 1978-1987 (Folder 44: 34)
      Includes typescript "Cleveland in the Evolution of Cities" by Porter
    - Poulos, John, 1979-1980 (Folder 44: 35)
      Includes obituary of Poulos
    - Povzea, Murray, 1978 (Folder 44: 36)
    - Prager, Rodolphe, 1984 (Folder 44: 37)
    - Radosh, Ronald, 1986-1991 (Folder 44: 38)
      Includes typescript letter to the editor by Radosh
    - Rauh, Joseph L., Jr., 1964-1967 (Folder 44: 39)
    - Reedy, George E., 1964-1997
      - 1964-1984 (Folder 45: 1)
      - 1985-1991 (Folder 45: 2)
      - 1992-1997 (Folder 45: 3)
    - Robins, Harold, 1981 (Folder 45: 4)
    - Roche, John P., 1973-1993 (Folder 45: 5)
      Includes writings by Roche
    - Rosemont, Franklin (and Charles H. Kerr Publishing Company), 1983-1997 (Folder 45: 6)
    - Rostow, Eugene V., 1978 (Folder 45: 7)
    - Roupe, Teresa, 1995 (Folder 45: 8)
    - Rustin, Bayard, 1971 (Folder 45: 9)
    - Ryan, Joseph, 1977 (Folder 45: 10)
    - Ryan, Sally, 1996 (Folder 45: 11)
    - Salisbury, Harrison (re Walter Held), 1983-1990 (Folder 45: 12)
    - Satir, Norman, 1961-1983 (Folder 45: 13)
    - Schoenfeld, Gabriel, 1984-1990 (Folder 45: 14)
      Includes typescript "Perestroika in the Provinces" by Schoenfeld
    - Schoenfeld, Oscar, 1988-1995 (Folder 45: 15)
    - Seabury, Paul, 1979-1980 (Folder 45: 16)
    - Shachtman, Max and Yetta, 1964-1978 (Folder 46: 1)
      Includes mimeograph "Comintern's Splinter Movements," "The Communist International and the National-Colonial Question," and outline of "A History of the Communist International," all by Shachtman; material re estate of Shachtman; and typescript memorial tribute to Yetta Shachtman by Saul Bellow
    - Shapiro, Meyer, 1994 (Folder 46: 2)
    - Shlyapnikova, Irina Aleksandrova, 1993 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Shube, Sam, 1987-1988 (Folder 46: 4)
    - Siegel, Paul, 1996 (Folder 46: 5)
    - Sinclair, Louis, 1980-1981 (Folder 46: 6)
    - Slaiman, Donald, 1980-1994 (Folder 46: 7)
    - Slavin, Morris, 1990-1997 (Folder 46: 8)
    - Sorin, Gerald (re Irving Howe), 1997 (Folder 46: 9)
    - Speyer, Edward, 1990 (Folder 46: 10)
    - Stamm, Tom, 1968-1980
      Includes Stamm's letters to others and writings re assassination of Leon Trotsky
      - 1968-1976 (Folder 46: 11)
      - 1977-1978 (Folder 46: 12)
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 46: 13)
    - Sterling, Max (to Alan Wald), undated (Folder 46: 14)
    - Stern, Will, 1979-1991 (Folder 46: 15)
    - Stolar, Abe and family, 1978-1995, undated
      - 1978-1988 (Folder 46: 16)
      - 1989-1995 (Folder 46: 17)
      - Undated (Folder 46: 18)
    - Strickland, Donald A., 1961 (Folder 47: 1)
    - Stuart, Jack, 1997 (Folder 47: 2)
    - Suall, Irwin and Joan, 1975-1997 (Folder 47: 3)
    - Susskind, David, 1978 (Folder 47: 4)
    - Swabeck, Arne, 1976 (Folder 47: 5)
    - Swados, Bette (to Alan Wald re Harvey Swados), 1974 (Folder 47: 6)
    - Tamiment Institute Library, 1981-1996 (Folder 47: 7)
      Includes Library bulletins and Oral History of the American Left newsletters
    - Thomas, Norman, 1960 (Folder 47: 8)
    - Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel, 1990-1997 (Folder 47: 9)
      Includes writings by Trachtenberg
    - Trilling, Diana, 1985 (Folder 47: 10)
    - Turnbull, Emily (and Prometheus Research Library), 1985-1998 (Folder 47: 11)
    - Van Heijenoort, Jean, 1983 (Folder 47: 12)
    - Vitali, Carlo (and Istituto di Studi sul Lavoro), 1982 (Folder 47: 13)
    - Volkov, Esteban and family, 1970-1997 (Folder 47: 14)
    - Wald, Alan, 1974-1997
      - 1974-1981 (Folder 47: 15)
      - 1982-1987 (Folder 47: 16)
      - 1988-1997 (Folder 47: 17)
      - Typescript writings by Wald: "The Line of Blood"; "Memories of the John Dewey Commission Forty Years Later"; "James T. Farrell's Studs Lonigan: Its Significance for American Radicalism"; obituaries of Bernard Wolfe and Jean Van Heijenoort; biographical articles on Felix Morrow, Dwight Macdonald, William Phillips, James T. Farrell, George Novack, James P. Cannon, and Philip Rahv, 1974-1997 (Folder 4718)
      - Printed writings by Wald, 1974-1997 (Folder 4719)
    - Ward, Ann, 1991 (Folder 48: 1)
      Includes obituaries of Frank Ward
    - Watts, Rowland, 1960-1961 (Folder 48: 2)
    - Weir, Stan (to Alan Wald), 1974 (Folder 48: 3)
    - Weissman, Muriel, 1985 (Folder 48: 4)
      Includes death notice of George L. Weissman
    - Weissman, Suzi, 1994-1997 (Folder 48: 5)
    - Westoby, Adam, 1980 (Folder 48: 6)
    - Widick, B. J., 1962 (Folder 48: 7)
      Includes printed articles about Widick
    - Williams, Kenneth, 1989-1990 (Folder 48: 8)
    - Willingham, Calder (to Alan Wald), 1983 (Folder 48: 9)
    - Wolfe, Albert, 1990-1991 (Folder 48: 10)
    - Woolley, Barry Lee, 1974-1975 (Folder 48: 11)
    - Worthington, Peter, 1994 (Folder 48: 12)
  - Speeches and writings by Albert Glotzer
    - Letter to the editor of the New Yorker re its review of Isaac Don Levine, The Mind of an Assassin, 1959 November 2 (date written). (Folder 48: 13)
    - "William Z. Foster,", 1961? (Folder 48: 14)
      Holograph notes, probably for speech following death of Foster
    - "New York Lexicon," The Transcript, 1964 March (Folder 48: 15)
    - Draft resolution on 1968 presidential election (New Chelsea Reform Democratic Club), 1967 October 24 (Folder 48: 16)
    - Statement of candidacy for Democratic state committeeman, circa 1967 (Folder 48: 17)
      Processed
    - Draft resolution on liberal-labor coalition (Americans for Democratic Action), 1969 June (Folder 48: 18)
    - Notes on the American Civil War and the American South, circa 1960s (Folder 48: 19)
    - "Democratic Left Should Back Ryan to Beat Bella," New America, 1972 April 28 (Folder 48: 20)
      Notes, typescript and printed copy
    - "Max Shachtman" (obituary), New America, 1972 November 15 (Folder 48: 21)
    - Memorial tribute to Max Shachtman, 1972 December 10 (Folder 48: 22)
    - "Development of Theory of Bureaucratic Collectivism,", 1973 March 7 (Folder 48: 23)
    - "Siqueiros: The Artist as Gunman,", 1974 (Folder 48: 24)
    - "Reminiscences of J. P. C." (intended as contribution to memorial volume for James P. Cannon), 1975 (Folder 48: 25)
      Typescript and printed background article
    - Ninetieth birthday tribute to E. R. McKinney, 1976 December 12 (Folder 48: 26)
      Typed notes and program
    - "On Eleanor Marx" (letter to the editor), Dissent, circa 1976 (Folder 48: 27)
    - "On Nationalization,", 1977 January 26 (Folder 48: 28)
    - "New Soviet Hero" (letter to the editor re Ramon Mercader), New Leader, 1977 November 21 (Folder 48: 29)
    - "Some Comments on the Feldman-Miller Statement on SD Perspectives,", circa 1977 (Folder 48: 30)
    - "Farrell's Courageous Stand against Literary Stalinism" (review of Alan Wald, James T. Farrell: The Revolutionary Socialist Years), New America, 1978 November (Folder 48: 31)
      Typescript and printed copy
    - "The Volkow Interview: Reconstructing the Facts" (letter to the editor re interview of Esteban Volkov), New Republic, circa 1978 December (Folder 48: 32)
    - Review of Irving Howe, Trotsky, 1979 January 26 (Folder 48: 33)
    - Memorial tribute to James T. Farrell, 1979 (Folder 48: 34)
    - "The New Polycentrism" (re Eurocommunism), circa 1970s (Folder 48: 35)
      Holograph and typed notes and background material
    - "New York Crisis,", circa 1970s (Folder 48: 36)
    - Notes on terrorism, circa 1970s (Folder 48: 37)
    - "Some Thoughts on Paul Porter's Views on Mixed Economy,", circa 1970s (Folder 48: 38)
      Holograph draft
    - "The Glotzer-Reedy-Farrell File" (re Alger Hiss and Whittaker Chambers), The Warbler, 1980 July (Folder 48: 39)
    - "The 1980 Presidential Elections" (draft resolution, Social Democrats, U.S.A.), 1980 August 24 (Folder 48: 40)
    - "Thomas Stamm" (memorial tribute), 1980 (Folder 48: 41)
    - Interview, 1981 July 2 (Folder 49: 1)
      Typed summary by unidentified interviewer with handwritten editorial comments by Glotzer
    - "New Book on Lovestoneites" (review of Robert J. Alexander, The Right Opposition: The Lovestoneites and the International Communist Opposition of the 1930s), New America, 1982 January/March (Folder 49: 2)
    - Deposition, Alan Gelfand vs. William French Smith et al. (U.S. District Court case re Socialist Workers Party), 1982 March 26 (Folder 49: 3)
      Transcript of oral testimony
    - "Skeletons in a Liberal's Closet" (re Yuri Andropov), New America, 1982 November/December (Folder 49: 4)
    - "Israel, Lebanon and Socialists, Left and Right,", circa 1982 (Folder 49: 5)
    - "Max Shachtman: A Political-Biographical Essay," Bulletin of the Tamiment Institute/Ben Josephson Library, 1983 April (Folder 49: 6)
    - "The Legacy of the Workers Party, 1940-1949: Recollections and Reflections" (proceedings of Tamiment Library/Oral History of the American Left Conference), 1983 May 6 (Folder 49: 7)
      Transcript including remarks by Glotzer, and other conference material
    - "Forty-Five Years Later" (re Socialist Workers Party), 1983. Typescript (Folder 49: 8)
    - Memorial tribute to E. R. McKinney, 1984 February 28 (Folder 49: 9)
      Typescript and program material
    - "Ernest Rice McKinney, 1886-1984" (obituary), New America, 1984 February (Folder 49: 10)
    - "Lillian Hellman" (letter to the editor), Vineyard Gazette, 1984 July 17 (Folder 49: 11)
    - Interview with Maurice Isserman, 1984 October 10 (Folder 49: 12)
      Transcript
    - "Chernenko and Things Russian,", 1984 (Folder 49: 13)
    - Report on Socialist Workers Party expulsions, 1985 January (Folder 49: 14)
    - "Hellman and Thoreau" (letter to the editor), Vineyard Gazette, 1985 February 15 (Folder 49: 15)
      Notes, typescript, printed copy, and printed articles provoking the letter
    - "Playing on Fear" (letter to the editor re foreign policy), Vineyard Gazette, 1985 March 22 (Folder 49: 16)
      Typescript, printed copy, and printed articles provoking the letter
    - Message to memorial meeting for George L. Weissman, 1985 May 25 (Folder 49: 17)
      Holograph and memorial material
    - "A Tribute for the Carlo Collection" (re political cartoonist Jesse "Carlo" Cohen), 1985 December 24 (Folder 49: 18)
      Typescript, correspondence with Joseph Cohen, and background material
    - Notes on neoconservatism, 1985, undated (Folder 49: 19)
    - Notes on supply-side economics, 1985, undated (Folder 49: 20)
    - Message to memorial meeting for George Breitman, 1986 June 7 (Folder 50: 1)
      Typescript and memorial material
    - "Sam Fishman: A Tribute," Notes (Social Democrats, U.S.A.), 1986 December (Folder 50: 2)
      Typescript, printed copy, obituaries of Fishman, and memorial meeting program
    - "Albert Goldman," in Bernard K. Johnpoll and Harvey Klehr, ed., Biographical Dictionary of the American Left, 1986 (Folder 50: 3)
      Notes, typescript, and correspondence with Jack Verblen
    - "Ernest Rice McKinney," in Bernard K. Johnpoll and Harvey Klehr, ed., Biographical Dictionary of the American Left, 1986 (Folder 50: 4)
      Notes, typescript, and background material
    - "Martin Abern," in Bernard K. Johnpoll and Harvey Klehr, ed., Biographical Dictionary of the American Left, 1986 (Folder 50: 5)
    - "Max Shachtman," in Bernard K. Johnpoll and Harvey Klehr, ed., Biographical Dictionary of the American Left, 1986 (Folder 50: 6)
    - "Refreshing Memories" (review of Sidney Hook, Out of Step: An Unquiet Life in the 20th Century), Forward, 1987 August 21 (Folder 50: 7)
    - Letter to the editor of the New York Times re Ramon Mercader, 1987 November 16 (date written) (Folder 50: 8)
    - "Russia (and China): Great Changes or Bureaucratic Timidity? A Preliminary Discussion" (speech, Social Democrats, U.S.A. national convention), 1987 December 4 (Folder 50: 9)
    - British Trotskyism in 1931," Revolutionary History, 1988 Spring (Folder 50: 10)
    - "Gorbachev, Prof. Cohen, History and the Case of Comrade Bukharin,", 1988 (Folder 50: 11)
    - Trotsky: Memoir and Critique, 1989
      - Outline and correspondence, 1989 (Folder 50: 12)
      - Notes and background material, 1989 (Folder 50: 13-14)
      - Holograph, 1989 (Folder 50: 15)
      - Typescript, 1989 (Folder 51: 1-2)
      - Reviews, 1989 (Folder 51: 3)
    - "Russian Histories" (letter to the editor re review by Alan Wald of Trotsky: Memoir and Critique), Washington Post Book World, 1990 March 4 (Folder 51: 4)
    - "Exiled to Alma-Ata" (letter to the editor re review of W. Bruce Lincoln, Red Victory), New York Times Book Review, 1990 March 25 (Folder 51: 5)
    - "Mencken and Trotsky" (letter to the editor of Commentary), 1990 (Folder 51: 6)
    - Interview with Bella Yezerskaya, 1991 (Folder 51: 7)
      Typed transcript
    - "The 1917 Revolution Should Never Have Taken Place" (contribution to symposium on Stalinism, the Left, and Beyond), Workers' Liberty, 1992 March 1 (Folder 51: 8)
    - "SD U.S.A.: Random Thoughts and Some Not So Random," Dialogue (Social Democrats, U.S.A.), 1992 March (Folder 51: 9)
    - Interview with Jack Stuart, circa 1992-1995 (Folder 51: 10)
    - "Arab Money Corrupts Trotskyists," Midstream, 1993 May (Folder 51: 11)
    - "On Irving Howe," Notes (Social Democrats, U.S.A.), 1993 May (Folder 51: 12)
    - "John P. Roche: In Memoriam," Notes (Social Democrats, U.S.A.), 1994 May/June (Folder 51: 13)
    - "Sam Gordon" (letter to the editor), Revolutionary History, 1994 Spring (Folder 51: 14)
    - "Rowland Watts" (obituary), 1995 February (Folder 51: 15)
    - "The Angry Intriguer with a Marble Pulse" (review of Lars T. Lih, Oleg V. Naumov and Oleg V. Khlevniuk, ed., Stalin's Letters to Molotov, 1925-1936), International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, 1995 Fall (Folder 51: 16)
    - "The Comintern's U.S. Legion: Stalin's American Division" (review of Harvey Klehr, John Earl Haynes and Fridrikh Igorevich Firsov, The Secret World of American Communism), International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, 1996 Spring (Folder 51: 17)
    - "The Brutal March Backward" (review of Dmitri Volkogonov, Lenin), International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, 1996 Fall (Folder 51: 18)
    - "Marx and the Jews: A Paradox of Sorts," Midstream, 1997 May (Folder 51: 19)
      Notes and typescript